ALEJANDRO MEDERO LUJÁN Software Developer

alexmedero10@gmail.com | 5560665787 | México City in: alejandromederolujan | • alexmedero10 | iii: Portfolio

ABOUT ME

I am a software developer with expertise in implementing, testing, and supporting software systems. I effectively apply development methodologies, such as SDLC and agile approaches, to ensure timely delivery. I utilize multiple platforms and programming languages, and I possess strong collaboration and teamwork skills, enabling me to contribute effectively in collaborative and productive work environments.

EDUCATION

Escuela Superior de Cómputo Bachelor in Computer Science Mexico August 2017 - December 2023

Tecmilenio

Mexico May 2024 - Current

Master in Artificial Intelligence

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, C/C++, SQL

Frameworks: Spring (Core, Boot, Cloud), JPA, Hibernate, JUnit, Eureka, Circuit Breaker

Tools: MySql, Confluence, Jira, Bitbucket, Git, Github, Postman

Development Platforms: STS, Visual Studio, Netbeans, Intellij IDEA **Soft Skills:** Teamwork, Problem solving, Adaptation

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM (Citibanamex) | Java Developer

June 2024 - Current

- Integrated a third-party system for real-time transaction analysis to detect potential fraud, optimizing the process by adding an hourly API call to streamline indicators retrieval.
- Conducted thorough testing using Postman and ensured smooth deployment while monitoring logs via Pivotal Cloud Foundry for prompt issue resolution.
- Enhanced fraud detection in cardless withdrawals and airtime recharges, significantly improving transaction security and user protection.

IBM (Citibanamex) | Java Developer

May 2023 - June 2024

- Identified and updated over 20 outdated dependencies with security vulnerabilities using Blackduck, reducing risks and increasing system reliability.
- Analyzed project dependencies to confirm usage, removed unused components, and ensured compatibility with the latest versions of Java, Spring, and other frameworks.
- Successfully minimized disruption by prioritizing high-risk updates and coordinating changes over a year-long effort.

CERTIFICATES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Enterprise Design Thinking Knowledge of the application of enterprise design thinking and its value.

Find opportunities to put it into practice in your daily work.

IBM Agile Explorer Understand the values, principles and

practices of Agile.

Microsoft Certified: Azure

Fundamentals

Basic knowledge of cloud concepts, core Azure services, and Azure

management and governance features and tools.

HackMX 2021 - Quantum

(Second place)

Simulator platform to carry out presidential votes.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Microservices Academy IBM (2022)

Microservices Development with Java and Spring, Creating and cosuming REST APIs, leveraging tools like Eureka, Gateway and Circuit Breaker.